<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.4//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.4/docbookx.dtd">

<section id="scheduler">
    <title>OTRS Scheduler</title>
    <para>
        The OTRS Scheduler is an independent system process that executes tasks in
background. These kind of processes are know as <emphasis>daemons</emphasis>
in Unix / Linux systems.  It is independent but that doesn't mean that the
Scheduler does everything alone, it is fully integrated into OTRS and can
use any OTRS module as needed to complete each task.
    </para>

    <para>
        For sanity reasons the Scheduler process needs to be restarted from time to
time. This is done automatically by the scheduler process itself once a day,
but it can be adjusted as needed using the SysConfig by editing the
"Scheduler::RestartAfterSeconds" setting.
    </para>
    <para>
        The OTRS Scheduler is a fully automated process, the only needed human
interaction is to check its status periodically and start or stop it as
needed.
    </para>
    <note>
        <para>
            If the Scheduler is stopped for any reason, all pending tasks and new tasks
registered when the Scheduler is stopped will be executed as soon as the
Scheduler starts again (unless the tasks are set to be executed in the
future).
        </para>
    </note>
    <section id="scheduler-gui">
        <title>Scheduler  - Grafisches Interface</title>
        <para>
            Der Scheduler ist nicht sichtbar in der grafischen Oberfläche von OTRS
solange er läuft.
        </para>
        <section id="scheduler-gui-notify">
            <title>Benachrichtigung: Scheduler läuft nicht.</title>
            <para>
                There are two different types of notifications if the system detects that
the scheduler is not running. This detection is based on the update
frequency of the Scheduler process. If the difference between current time
and the last process update time is 2 times the process update frequency a
warning message will be displayed in the OTRS notification area. If it is
over 4 times the process frequency then an alert will be displayed instead.
            </para>
            <para>
                Die Aktualisierungszeit des Schedulers kann in der SysConfig in der
Einstellung "Scheduler::PIDUpdateTime" konfiguriert werden
            </para>
            <para>
                If you see a warning message it is not always necessary to take an action,
but it is highly recommended to check if the scheduler process is
running. If you see an alert, then there is a high chance that the scheduler
is in fact not running and should be started.
            </para>
            <para>
                By default the Scheduler not running notification is enabled, if there is a
valid web service registered in the database, and is only displayed to the
users in the "admin" group.
            </para>
            <para>
                To disable the notification (not recommended) or to change or add the
notification groups, please edit the
"Frontend::NotifyModule###800-Scheduler-Check" setting in the SysConfig.
            </para>
            <para>
                <screenshot>
<screeninfo>Scheduler Benachrichtigung</screeninfo> <graphic srccredit="scheduler
notification - screenshot" scale="40"
fileref="screenshots/scheduler-notify.png"></graphic></screenshot>
            </para>
            <para>
                <emphasis>Abbildung: Scheduler Benachrichtigung.</emphasis>
            </para>
        </section>
        <section id="scheduler-gui-start">
            <title>Scheduler starten</title>
            <para>
                By clicking on the Scheduler not running notification link (either warning
or alert) a dialog box will open to let you start the Scheduler process
again. The Scheduler can be started normally or forced to start, by clicking
on the appropriate check box in the dialog.
            </para>
            <note>
                <para>
                    A forced Scheduler start is only necessary if previous Scheduler process was
terminated abnormally and the Process ID is still registered in the
database.
                </para>
                <para>
                    To have full control of the Scheduler process and to check it real status
please use the command line tools described below.
                </para>
            </note>
            <para>
                <screenshot>
<screeninfo>Scheduler starten</screeninfo> <graphic srccredit="scheduler start
- screenshot" scale="40"
fileref="screenshots/scheduler-start.png"></graphic></screenshot>
            </para>
            <para>
                <emphasis>Abbildung: Start Scheduler.</emphasis>
            </para>
        </section>
    </section>
    <section id="scheduler-cli">
        <title>Scheduler-Befehlszeilenoberfläche</title>
        <para>
            The Scheduler command line tools let you control the Scheduler process
(Start / Stop) or query it status. There are also tools to register the
process to be controlled by the operating system.
        </para>
        <para>
            Included with OTRS there commandline interface (CLI) tools for the
scheduler.
        </para>
        <section id="scheduler-cli-linux-init">
            <title>Scheduler init.d Dateien</title>
            <para>
                Init.d files are special scripts that are called by the operating system at
startup and shutdown.
            </para>
            <para>
                OTRS provides init.d scripts to start / stop the OTRS Scheduler process
automatically by the operating system. These scripts are located under
OTRS_HOME/scripts.
            </para>
            <para>
                The init.d scripts need to be copied to the correct location for your
operating system. They need to have the proper permissions and some internal
variables need to be set to work properly. If you used the OTRS RPMs to set
up the system, this is taken care of automatically.
            </para>
            <itemizedlist mark="round">
                <title>interne Werte des Init.d Skript</title>
                <listitem>
                    <para>
                        <command>OTRS_HOME</command> -  Der Installationspfad von OTRS.
                    </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>
                        <command>User</command> - Der Benutzer unter dem Apache ausgeführt wird.
                    </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>
                        <command>Group</command> -  Die Gruppe unter dem Apache ausgeführt wird.
                    </para>
                </listitem>
            </itemizedlist>
            <note>
                <para>
                    Zur Zeit bietet OTRS init.d-Skripte nur für Linux-Plattformen an.
                </para>
            </note>
            <table>
                <title>Liste der init-Skripte und der unterstützten Betriebssysteme</title>
                <tgroup cols="2">
                <thead>
                    <row>
                        <entry>Init-Skript</entry>
                        <entry>Unterstützte Betriebssysteme</entry>
                    </row>
                </thead>
                <tbody>
                    <row>
                        <entry>OTRS Scheduler Linux</entry>
                        <entry>Red Hat, Fedora, CentOS, SUSE, openSUSE, Debian, Ubuntu</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>otrs-scheduler-gentoo-init.d, otrs-scheduler-gentoo-conf.d</entry>
                        <entry>Gentoo</entry>
                    </row>
                </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
            <example>
                <title>Ein Beispiel wie der OTRS Scheduler unter Linux gestartet wird.</title>
                <para>
                    <screen>
                        shell> /etc/init.d/otrs-scheduler-linux start
                    </screen>
                </para>
            </example>
            <itemizedlist mark="round">
                <title>Verfügbare Aktionen</title>
                <listitem>
                    <para>
                        <command>start</command> startet den OTRS Scheduler
                    </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>
                        <command>stop</command> stoppt den OTRS Scheduler.
                    </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>
                        <command>restart</command> startet den OTRS Scheduler neu.
                    </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>
                        <command>status</command> Statusabfrage des OTRS Schedulers
                    </para>
                </listitem>
            </itemizedlist>
            <para>
                Der Scheduler benötigt die Datenbank um die Prozess ID zu registrieren. Aus
diesem Grund sind folgende Dinge notwendig:
                <itemizedlist mark="round">
                    <listitem>
                        <para>
                            Execute the Scheduler init.d script to <emphasis>start</emphasis> the
Scheduler process after the database process is up and running.
                        </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>
                            Execute the Scheduler init.d script to <emphasis>stop</emphasis> the
Scheduler before the database process shuts down.
                        </para>
                    </listitem>
                </itemizedlist>
            </para>
            <note>
                <para>
                    If you want the Scheduler to run at system startup, please read the
documentation of the operating system to find out the right location to
place the init.d scripts, how to configure them to run automatically and how
to set the run order.
                </para>
            </note>
        </section>
        <section id="scheduler-cli-linux-daemon">
            <title>Zeitplaner-Hitergrunddatei</title>
            <para>
                This is the part of the Scheduler that stays running in the background
checking for tasks to execute. It also provides the main functions to
control the process.
            </para>
            <para>
                Alle Unix / Linux Betriebsysteme nutzen die Datei
<command>OTRS_HOME/bin/otrs.Scheduler.pl</command>.
            </para>
            <example>
                <title>Ein Beispiel wie der OTRS Scheduler gestartet wird.</title>
                <para>
                    <screen>
                        shell> OTRS_HOME/bin/otrs.Scheduler.pl -a start
                    </screen>
                </para>
            </example>
            <itemizedlist mark="round">
                <title>Verfügbare Optionen</title>
                <listitem>
                    <para>
                        <command>-a </command> Aktion.
                    </para>
                    <itemizedlist mark="round">
                        <title>mögliche Werte</title>
                        <listitem>
                            <para>
                                <command>start</command>- startet den Scheduler.
                            </para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                            <para>
                                <command>stop</command>- stoppt den Scheduler.
                            </para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                            <para>
                                <command>status</command>- fragt den Status des Scheduler ab.
                            </para>
                        </listitem>
                    </itemizedlist>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>
                        <command>-f </command> erzwingt das starten oder stoppen des Scheduler.
                    </para>
                </listitem>
            </itemizedlist>
            <example>
                <title>Beispiel für das erzwungene stoppen des OTRS Scheduler.</title>
                <para>
                    <screen>
                        shell> OTRS_HOME/bin/otrs.Scheduler.pl -a stop -f 1
                    </screen>
                </para>
            </example>
            <note>
                <para>
                    Das erzwungene stoppen des Schedulers wird verwendet um die Prozess ID aus
der Datenbank zu entfernen wenn der Scheduler nicht läuft, aber der Prozess
registriert ist
                </para>
                <para>
                    Das erzwungene starten des Schedulers wird verwendet wenn der Scheduler
nicht läuft, aber der Prozess registriert ist
                </para>
                <para>
                    Force start or stop are only necessary if the start of the process is needed
to be done before the process update time expires. Otherwise an expired
entry in the database is discarded by normal start.
                </para>
            </note>
        </section>
    </section>
</section>
