<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE appendix PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.4//EN"
  "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.4/docbookx.dtd">

<appendix id="additional-resources">
<title>Additional Resources</title>

    <para>
    We try to support you with the very latest information about OTRS. We also give you an opportunity to provide us with your feedback.
    </para>

    <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
            <term>otrs.com</term>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    The OTRS website with source code, documentation and news is available at
                    <ulink url="http://otrs.org/">http://www.otrs.com/</ulink>.
                    Here you can also find information about commercial services and trainings from OTRS Group,
                    the creator of OTRS.
                </para>
                <para>
                    For services (support, consulting, development, and training) you can contact the company behind OTRS, OTRS AG. Our offices are located in Germany, USA, Mexico, the Netherlands, and in other countries. Visit our website for <ulink url="http://www.otrs.com/buy">contact information</ulink>.
                </para>
            </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
            <term>Mailing Lists</term>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    <table id="additional-resources-mailinglists-table">
                        <title>Mailinglists</title>
                          <tgroup cols="3">
                            <thead>
                              <row>
                                <entry>
                                  Name
                                </entry>
                                <entry>
                                  Description
                                </entry>
                                <entry>
                                  Homepage
                                </entry>
                              </row>
                            </thead>
                            <tbody>
                              <row>
                                <entry>
                                  announce@otrs.org
                                </entry>
                                <entry>
                                  Low traffic list, in English, for announcements of new OTRS releases and security issues.
                                </entry>
                                <entry>
                                  <ulink url="http://lists.otrs.org/cgi-bin/listinfo/announce">
                                  <citetitle>http://lists.otrs.org/cgi-bin/listinfo/announce</citetitle>
                                  </ulink>
                                </entry>
                              </row>
                              <row>
                                <entry>
                                  otrs@otrs.org
                                </entry>
                                <entry>
                                  Medium to high traffic list, in English, where you can find all sorts of relevant questions and support for the product.
                                </entry>
                                <entry>
                                  <ulink url="http://lists.otrs.org/cgi-bin/listinfo/otrs">
                                  <citetitle>http://lists.otrs.org/cgi-bin/listinfo/otrs</citetitle>
                                  </ulink>
                                </entry>
                              </row>
                              <row>
                                <entry>
                                  otrs-de@otrs.org
                                </entry>
                                <entry>
                                  Medium to high traffic list, in German, where you can find all sorts of relevant questions and support for the product.
                                </entry>
                                <entry>
                                  <ulink url="http://lists.otrs.org/cgi-bin/listinfo/otrs-de">
                                  <citetitle>http://lists.otrs.org/cgi-bin/listinfo/otrs-de</citetitle>
                                  </ulink>
                                </entry>
                              </row>
                              <row>
                                <entry>
                                  dev@otrs.org
                                </entry>
                                <entry>
                                  Medium traffic list, in English, where the OTRS developers discuss various design and implementation issues.
                                </entry>
                                <entry>
                                  <ulink url="http://lists.otrs.org/cgi-bin/listinfo/dev">
                                  <citetitle>http://lists.otrs.org/cgi-bin/listinfo/dev</citetitle>
                                  </ulink>
                                </entry>
                              </row>
                              <row>
                                <entry>
                                  i18n@otrs.org
                                </entry>
                                <entry>
                                  Low traffic list, in English, for internationalization and localization questions. If you are or want to become a translator of the OTRS project or have any problems with one of our applications in an international environment, this is where you should connect.
                                </entry>
                                <entry>
                                  <ulink url="http://lists.otrs.org/cgi-bin/listinfo/i18n">
                                  <citetitle>http://lists.otrs.org/cgi-bin/listinfo/i18n</citetitle>
                                  </ulink>
                                </entry>
                              </row>
                            </tbody>
                          </tgroup>
                        </table>
                </para>
            </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
            <term>Bug tracking</term>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    To report software defects, please visit <ulink url="http://bugs.otrs.org/">http://bugs.otrs.org/</ulink>
    (see Figure below). Please take note of the difference between a bug and a configuration issue. Configuration issues are problems that you encounter when setting a system, or general questions regarding the use of OTRS. Bug reports should only be used for issues with the source code of OTRS or other open source OTRS modules itself. For configuration issues, you should either use the <ulink url="http://www.otrs.com/solutions/service-contracts/">commercial support, available from OTRS.com</ulink>, or the public mailing lists.
                </para>
                <para>
                    <figure>
                        <title>Bugtracking Tool</title>
                        <screenshot>
                             <graphic scale="40" fileref="screenshots/bugs-otrs-org.png"></graphic>
                        </screenshot>
                    </figure>
                </para>
                <para>
                    You help us a lot to improve the product by reporting bugs. We appreciate your input!
                </para>
            </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
    </variablelist>

</appendix>
