<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.4//EN"
  "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.4/docbookx.dtd">

<section id="upgrade-windows-installer">
<title>Обновление с помощью Windows Installer</title>
<para>
If you installed OTRS on Windows, it is possible to upgrade seamlessly by
downloading the new Windows Installer and running it.  The installer will
automatically detect the OTRS installation and perform an upgrade on it. The
installer will stop the OTRS services and start them after the installation
is complete, so your users will experience downtime. Make sure you plan some
time for the upgrade. Always make sure you have a backup of your server
before you start the upgrade procedure!
</para>

<section id="upgrade-windows-installer-patch">
<title>Performing patch level upgrades on Windows</title>
<para>
If you need to install a 'patch level' upgrade (i.e. from OTRS 3.3.1 to OTRS
3.3.2) on Windows all you need to do is to download and run the new
installer. Of course you should make sure you have a backup in place before
you start the upgrade!
</para>
</section>

<section id="upgrade-windows-installer-minor">
<title>Performing minor level upgrades on Windows</title>
<para>
Minor upgrades (from OTRS 3.2 to OTRS 3.3) take a little more time as there
is also a database upgrade step involved. The installer will detect this and
will automatically perform the upgrade for you.  After installation you
should still perform steps 12, 13 and 14 of the 'regular' <link
linkend="upgrading">upgrading section</link>.
</para>
<para>
Please note that if you have any additional packages such as Feature Add-Ons
installed on your OTRS system, you'll need to upgrade these as well. Make
sure you obtain these before you start the upgrade. After upgrade is
complete you can upgrade these packages via the Package Installer Web GUI.
Packages from the 'standard' repositories such as Survey, FAQ and ITSM can
be upgraded from the Package Manager after the framework upgrade is
complete.
</para>
</section>

</section>
