<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.4//EN"
  "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.4/docbookx.dtd">

<section id="time">
<title>時間関連機能</title>

<section id="time-settings">
<title>業務時間、祝祭日とタイムゾーンの設定</title>

<para>
Some functions in OTRS, like escalations and <link
linkend="unlock-tickets">automatic unlocking of tickets</link>, depend on a
proper configuration of business hours, time zones and holidays. You can
define these via the <link linkend="sysconfig">SysConfig interface</link>,
in <link linkend="ConfigReference_Framework:Core::Time">Framework &gt;
Core::Time</link>.  You can also specify different sets of business hours,
holidays and time zones as separate 'Calendars' in <link
linkend="ConfigReference_Framework:Core::Time::Calendar1">Framework &gt;
Core::Time::Calendar1</link> through <link
linkend="ConfigReference_Framework:Core::Time::Calendar9">Framework &gt;
Core::Time::Calendar9</link>. Calendars can be defined by <link
linkend="adminarea-queue">queue settings</link>, or on SLA levels. This
means that, for example, you can specify a calendar with 5 x 8 business
hours for your 'standard' SLA, but create a separate calendar with 7 x 24
support for your 'gold' SLA; as well as set a calendar for your
'Support-USA' queue with a different time window than your 'Support-Japan'
queue. OTRS can handle up to 99 different calendars.
</para>

<section id="TimeWorkingHours">
<title>業務時間</title>

<para>
Set up the working hours for your system in SysConfig <link
linkend="ConfigReference_Framework:Core::Time:TimeWorkingHours">Framework
&gt; Core::Time::TimeWorkingHours</link>, or for your specific calendar in
the calendar's configuration. OTRS can handle a granularity of one
hour. Checking the marks in the boxes 8, 9, 10 ... 17 corresponds with
business hours of 8 AM - 6 PM.
</para>

<para>
業務時間内にのみエスカレーション・チケットを作成することができます。エスカレーションの通知や送信された保留チケットロックされていないチケットも同様です。
</para>
</section>


<section id="TimeVacationDays">
<title>固定の期日、祝祭日</title>

<para>
Holidays that are on a fixed date every year, such as New Year's Day or the
Fourth of July, can be specified in <link
linkend="ConfigReference_Framework:Core::Time:TimeVacationDays">TimeVacationDays</link>,
or in the corresponding section for the calendars 1-9.
</para>

<para>
チケットはエスカレーションしませんしまた、TimeVacationDaysに定義された日付にアンロックされません。
</para>

<note>
<para>
OTRS出荷のデフォルトで<emphasis>ドイツの</emphasis>祝祭日をインストールしています。
</para>
</note>

</section>

<section id="TimeVacationDaysOneTime">
<title>TimeVacationDaysOneTime</title>

<para>
Holidays such as Easter that do not have a yearly fixed date but instead
vary each year, can be specified in <link
linkend="ConfigReference_Framework:Core::Time:TimeVacationDaysOneTime">TimeVacationDaysOneTime</link>.
</para>

<para>
チケットはエスカレーションしませんしまた、TimeVacationDaysに定義された日付にアンロックされません。
</para>

<note>
<para>
OTRSは、一度だけの休日をつけて出荷しません。イースターまたは感謝祭のような休日はOTRSを構成する際にご自身でシステムに追加して下さい。
</para>
</note>

</section>

</section>

<section id="unlock-tickets">
<title>自動アンロック</title>

<para>
ロックされたチケットは、システムによって自動的に対応中にすることができます。この機能はこんな場合に有用でしょう。例えば、担当者が処理される必要のあるチケットをロックしているが、彼が何らかの理由でそれらを処理できなければ、「彼は今緊急の用事のためオフィスの外にいます」ということができます。自動アンロック機能は、ロックされたチケットがないことが忘れられないことを確実にするために与えられた時間の後でチケットをアンロックします。
</para>

<para>
チケットが対応中にされる前の時間の量は、すべてのキューのための<link
linkend="adminarea-queue">キュー設定</link>の中で指定することができます。モジュール
<filename>bin/otrs.UnlockTickets.pl</filename>（cronジョブとして周期的に実行される)は、チケットの自動アンロックします。アンロック中のチケットに関する通知は以下の担当者のみに送信されます。
</para>

<para>
「マイ・キュー」にあるアンロックされたチケット・セットを持つキューを持っている担当者。個人的<link
linkend="user-preferences">選択（選好）</link>のアンロック・チケットに関する通知を活性化した担当者。
</para>

<para>
次の条件がすべて満たされれば、チケットはアンロックされます:
</para>

<itemizedlist>
<listitem>
<para>
チケットがあるキューのために定義された<emphasis>アンロック・タイムアウト</emphasis>があります。
</para>
</listitem>
<listitem>
<para>
チケットは<emphasis>ロック済</emphasis>にセットされています。
</para>
</listitem>
<listitem>
<para>
チケットの状態は<emphasis>対応中</emphasis>です。
</para>
</listitem>
</itemizedlist>

<para>
アンロック・タイマーは担当者がチケットに新しい外部記事を追加すればリセットされます。それは次のタイプのうちのいずれかでしょう。:
<emphasis>外部Eメール</emphasis>、<emphasis>電話</emphasis>、<emphasis>ファックス</emphasis>、<emphasis>sms</emphasis>あるいは<emphasis>外部ノート</emphasis>。
</para>

<para>
さらに、チケット中の最後の記事が担当者によって作成され、顧客が別のものを加えれば、ウェブあるいはEメール応答のいずれかによって、アンロック・タイマーはリセットされるでしょう。
</para>

<para>
アンロック・タイマーをリセットする最後のイベントは、チケットがもう一人の担当者にいつ割り当てられるかです。
</para>

</section>

</section>
